gabi branco

Multidisciplinary professional fluent in business and tech. 7+ years delivering projects with users as the center of the process. I guide teams towards decision-making based on metrics and feedback to come up with solutions for real-life problems. My training in tech allows me to look for the most efficient, cost-effective and scalable ways to address user's pains. My experience as a mentor taught me how to appropriately use resources, understand assets, accommodate skills and care not only about product, but about people. My background in Journalism drives me to write, ask questions, listen, document, be empathetic. I'm a reporter and a user advocate.

professional experience

LE WAGON | Teacher and Product Manager since July 2018

As a mentor, I help aspiring entrepreneurs to deliver solutions to real life problems. I make sure teams keep their focus on user stories and shape scope through balancing value and deliverability, having the opportunity to train multidisciplinary groups in Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo, Amsterdam, Brussels and Tel Aviv.

- >> Under my guidance, 40+ web applications came to life;
- >> Empowered 230+ mentees to transform dreams into businesses;
- >> Taught concepts about Ruby, OOP, database, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails and product development.

Project Queen! I don't know if half of the products would have been completed without her help. (Nickoma Caesar, Tel Aviv, 2019)

AME DIGITAL | Product Owner from January 2019 to August 2019 (São Paulo)

Lead a multidisciplinary squad in a fintech startup. Dealing with stakeholders; prioritizing backlog and collecting data to make better decisions were some of my attributions.

- >> Managed third party developers to deliver a promotional tool, saving over 50% of revenue run rate on client acquisition costs;
- >> Created a message-delivery system to make users aware of new features and promotions;
- >> Integrated a face-recognition feature to prevent frauds, reducing significant losses.

GRUPO RBS

Editor from March 2017 to April 2018 (NYC)

Created and edited content; managed Public Relations team for a travel digital product.

Freelance Reporter from August 2015 to March 2017 (NYC)

Did freelance reporting, writing about Fashion Week, Women's March and more.

Journalist from April 2011 to August 2015 (Porto Alegre)

Wrote for two of the major columns of the newspaper, online and print, starting as an intern and being promoted three times. Produced two awarded web-series.

education

LE WAGON AMSTERDAM | Batch #154 from April to July 2018

9-week intensive coding bootcamp learning HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES2015, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails.

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul | B.S. Communications - Journalism